Guide to the Michael Scherker research files,1989.
Scherker, Michael research files, 1989.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Michael Scherker research files, 1989.
7568
Michael. Scherker
.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files pertaining to research on the 1969 Stonewall Riot.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files pertaining to research on the 1969 Stonewall Riot, in which the New York City Police Department and the gay community on Christopher Street came into violent conflict; includes Federal Bureau of Investigation files on the Gay Liberation Front and the Mattachine Society of New York acquired under the New York State Freedom of Information law; also correspondence with NYPD and FBI concerning the release of the papers. Also, correspondence to gay press re publicity for his project, single issues of papers mentioning it; and anonymous Christian literature addressed to Scherker and responses to the Stonewall project.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Scherker, Michael.; Gay Liberation front.; Mattachine Society of New York.
Subjects:
Gay liberation movement.; Gays.; Riots.; Stonewall Riot, New York, N. Y., 1969.; Sex discrimination.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a partial finding aid containing the list of informants for the Stonewall Oral History Project.
  - Christopher Street Liberation Day Movement, 1956-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wolfenden Committee and Homosexuality as a Criminal Offense, 1958-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mattachine Review and Newsletter-1 (Dec 59- Feb 64), 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arrested for Being Gay, 1959-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mattachine Review and Newsletter-2 (June 59- March 84), 1959-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mattachine Review and Newsletter-3 (June 59- May 85), 1959-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mattachine Review-1 (April- July), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mattachine Review-2 (August- Sept), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mattachine Review and Image (March 61- June 84), 1961-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mattachine Newsletter (Jan 63- Dec 64), 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mattachine Society and Review, 1969-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Homosexual Information Center- William Edward Glover, 1969-1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights- 1, 1969-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - FOI- NYPD, 1969-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Contact Sheets, 1971-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Contact Sheets, 1979-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights- 2, 1981-1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kevin B., 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Notes, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - FOI-FBI/HQ, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - FOI- General Information- 1, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - FOI- General Information- 2, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Michael Sherker Files, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Leon Friedman, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Contact Sheets, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conversation- Notes, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Michael Sherker- Stonewall, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Michael Sherker- Stonewall Correspondece and LGBT Publications, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Oral History Conference Panel, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Windy City Times, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Gay Times (Magazine)/ Windy City Times (Newspaper), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Interviewees, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)